digital-topo-maps.com 2017-08-18

# Digital-Topo-Maps.com Privacy Policy

Digital Map Store, LLC sells topographic maps, map software, waterproof writing supplies and other outdoor items. No log-in is required to use our site and we do not passively collect information from our visitors that would personally identify them in any way. Any information that would personally identify a visitor is typed into our website voluntarily by the visitor.   

##### Visitor Information Logged

Our server logs each visit to our site and records the pages that have been viewed. We use this information to understand how visitors engage our website and to enable us to make informed decisions about developing new content. The logs do not contain personal information about any user and no attempt is made to identify individual users or their usage habits.   
Information collected includes: 

  * URL web addresses that send traffic to our website (these are search engines and other websites that included a link to our website)
  * IP addresses (a unique number assigned to a computer when it connects to the Internet) of visitors that enter our website
  * The types of browsers (e.g., Netscape, Internet Explorer, Firefox) used to access our site
  * The operating system (Windows, Unix) used to access our site
  * The date and time for each visitor's access
  * The URLs of pages viewed by our visitors

We do not share the contents of our visitor log files with anyone outside of our company. The only reason that we would release this information is if it is requested by a law enforcement or government agency for the purpose of an essential investigation.   

##### Information Voluntarily Provided by Visitors

We welcome feedback about our website and responds to many information requests from visitors each day. These communications are done by email messages initiated by our website visitors. We will use the information associated with your message to prepare a reply but no information from your inquiry is shared with anyone outside of our company. We do not maintain an email list of visitors who correspond with us and do not send unsolicited messages to those who contact us.   

##### Credit Card Transactions

Our website has a store where visitors can make purchases. The shopping cart of this store operates through the use of session cookies. These cookies are small files that are placed on a visitor's computer to allow that computer to temporarily remember information about an order in progress. These cookies only contain information that allows our shopping cart to remember which items have been selected for purchase. No personal information is contained within the cookie and they expire when the shopper restarts his/her computer. 

In the checkout process the visitor must type in name, address and credit card information. This information is not stored in the cookie but is transmitted by secure connections to [Ultracart.com](http://www.ultracart.com/) (our shopping cart provider), [Authorize.net](http://authorize.net/) (our credit card processor) and the website visitor's credit card bank. This information is only used to complete the credit card transaction, ship the merchandise to the visitor and communicate with the visitor about the status of an order. During the checkout process the customer can check a box that will invite us to send them information about sales or special offers. We are the only user of this information and we never share customer purchase information with anyone outside of our business. Ultracart.com and Authorize.net have similar policies and do not release any information about our customers. 

##### Links to Other Websites

To assist our visitors, we sometimes link out to other websites that have related content. When you click on one of these links you will be leaving our website. When we link to a website, we always review that site to be sure that it has quality content and to be sure that it is a site that we would recommend to our colleagues, friends, and members of our family. We do not control the content of these websites and encourage any visitor to contact us if you feel that one of these sites contains information that is unsuitable for visitors of any age.   

##### Advertisements

We display the ads of companies that have directly contracted with us. All contracted ads are approved by us and the advertiser's website is inspected at the beginning of each advertising term. Each of these ads leads to a website that we would recommend to our colleagues, friends and members of our own family. 

We also display ads that are part of the Google Adsense program. Google has a [privacy policy for ads](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html) that explains the information obtained through their advertising and how that information is handled. Visitors can also learn how Google ads are customized to their interest or specify their interests via the [Google Ads Preferences Manager](http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/view?sig=ACi0TCggC8IxqZHvXJEl6c1Y-P4Y3V40-awnrh4WE7b6Z9N5N8ZBZ0i_YRmIk650eWpf8ABM2inG7fGn3vN-A1kIFfPZfbyd_PCPQn_CO9cE1EnX4IgoryX1tTyO14RkGykEYlOk_6zXAkhrUc2kdf7NbubcIcHpZxcV4enYWb3ulwMclK_hQQiqbi0azi-3mYyG8X4aKRR8ZPxajfCjFKvmktjHM2JPOWjOdFCBwEf5cPnIs8cTZgJxBOJlGFNcB0D_5QyaJ5a2&hl=en). 

Google's advertisers are also required to comply with the [Google Ad Content Policy](https://adwords.google.com/select/contentpolicy.html). We regularly inspect the ads that appear on our site and believe that Google does a very good job of delivering ad content that matches the topics of our website and the interest of our visitors. In the few instances that we have seen an ad that contained questionable content we immediately installed manual filters to ban future ads from that advertiser's website. 

Google and other advertisers on our site use technology such as cookies, web beacons or the [DoubleClick DART Cookie](http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/faq.aspx). These send advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdSense program) information including your IP address, your ISP, the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed or other viewing software installed. This is generally used for geotargeting purposes (showing New York real estate ads to someone in New York, for example) or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited (such as showing cooking ads to someone who frequents cooking sites). You can easily opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html). 

You can choose to disable or selectively turn off our cookies or third-party cookies in your browser settings, or by managing preferences in programs such as Norton Internet Security. However, this can affect how you are able to interact with our site as well as other websites. This could include the inability to login to services or programs, such as logging into forums or online email accounts.

##### Interaction with Children 

Our website complies with the [Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA)](http://www.ftc.gov/ogc/coppa1.htm). We make no attempt to passively or actively collect information from children. Children are able to write to us on their own initiative and we will reply to them on a one-time basis to respond to their request. We will not recontact them for other reasons or share any details of their contact with anyone. Transactions in our store are not knowingly accepted from children.   

##### Getting in Touch With Us 

This website is owned by Digital Map Store of Uniontown, Pennsylvania. The best way to get in touch with us is by email using the address below. We normally reply within 24 hours of message receipt.
